RG 030, Council of Defense
Connecticut State Library
- Series 14. Woman's Division
  - 74. Classified file, 1917-1919
    - T19.9: Hebrew translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.10: Armenian translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T19.11: Hungarian translations and correspondence (Box 363)
    - T20: Americanization Work Polish and Italian rallies (Box 363)
    - T20: Foreign born (Box 363)
    - Mrs. Chandler (Box 363)
    - T20.02: Mr. Spellacy (Box 363)
    - T20.03: Foreign men (local committees) (Box 363)
    - Americans to help with foreign born (Box 363)
    - T20.05: Statistics concerning foreign born (Box 363)
    - T20.06: Meeting, 1918 February 21 (Box 363)
    - T20.07: Dr. Jane E Robbins, Miss Mary Bushnell (Box 363)
    - T20.08: Italian Sub Committee (Box 363)
    - T20.16: National Committee Americanization (Box 363)
    - T20.200: Foreign born, Towns, Fairfield County (Box 364)
    - T20.300: Foreign born, Towns, Hartford County (Box 364)
    - T20.400: Foreign born, Towns, Litchfield County (Box 364)
    - T20.500: Foreign born, Towns, Middlesex County (Box 364)
    - T20.600: Foreign born, Towns, New Haven County (Box 364)
    - T20.700: Foreign born, Towns, New London County (Box 364)
    - T20.800: Foreign born, Towns, Tolland County (Box 364)
    - T20.900: Foreign born, Towns, Windham County (Box 364)
    - T21: Circular letters (Box 364)
    - T21.100: Circular letters to town chairmen, 2 folders (Box 364)
    - T22: The Woman's Committee in other states (Box 364)
    - T22: Correspondence with the states other than Connecticut (Box 364)
    - T23: A.C.A. (Box 365)
    - T24: Civil Service (Box 365)
    - T25: Food exhibits (Box 365)
    - T25: C.R.A. (Box 365)
    - T25.01: Suggestions for patriotic food exhibit (Box 365)
    - T25.02: Food fair clippings (Box 365)
    - T25.03: Diets (Box 365)
    - T25.04: Recipes, Miscellaneous (Box 365)
    - T25.06: Description of patriotic food exhibit (Box 365)
    - T25.07: Recipes - food fair (Box 366)
    - T25.16: National Committee food exhibits (Box 366)
    - T25.09: Reports food exhibits (Box 366)
    - T25.200: Food exhibits: Fairfield County (Box 366)
    - T25.300: Food exhibits: Hartford County (Box 366)
    - T25.400: Food exhibits: Litchfield County (Box 366)
    - T25.500: Food exhibits: Middlesex County (Box 366)
    - T25.600: Food exhibits: New Haven County (Box 366)
    - T25.700: Food exhibits: New London County (Box 366)
    - T25.800: Food exhibits: Tolland County (Box 366)
    - T25.900: Food exhibits: Windham County (Box 366)
    - T26: Information for probationers concerning Connecticut Hospital Training Schools (Box 366)
    - T26: Miscellaneous material in regard to recruiting student nurses, 3 folders (Box 367)
    - T26.16: National Committee on Recruiting of Student Nurses (Box 367)
    - T27: Information concerning war work for women (Box 367)
    - T27.1: Applications for war work (Box 367)
    - T27: Volunteers (Box 367)
    - T27: Women in war work (Box 367)
    - T27.2: Applications for paid positions with Woman's Committee and State Council (Box 367)
    - T29: Yarns (Box 368)
    - T30: Fraser, Helen; G. Arnold Shaw, Publisher (Box 368)
    - T31.1: Correspondence re arrangements for Miss Fraser's meetings, 1918 June 1-8 (Box 368)
    - T31: State Board of Education (Box 368)
    - T32: Correspondence re Conference on Girls' Work (Box 368)
    - T32: Conference of Charities and Corrections (George L. Warren) (Box 368)
    - T33: Data Department (Box 368)
    - T34: Correspondence re State Fair exhibit (Box 368)
    - T34.1: Correspondence re smaller circuits (Box 368)
    - T34.2: Itemized statements re Fairs, budget material for fairs, itemized bills (Box 368)
    - T50: Salvage, 2 folders (Box 369)
    - T51: Motor Messenger (Box 369)
    - T52: Publicity - Mrs. Richard M. Bissell (Box 369)
    - T52: Transferred - Mrs. Seton (Box 369)
    - T52: Transferred - Replies & questionnaires (Box 369)
    - T52.01: Publicity, Correspondence with Publicity Committee (Box 369)
    - T52.02: Patriotic literature (Box 369)
    - T52.03: Tobacco (Box 369)
    - T52.02: Publications of the Woman's Committee, Conn. Division (Box 369)
    - Pamphlets for publication (Box 369)
    - T52.1: Correspondence regarding photographs appearing in Hartford newspapers (Box 369)
    - Freeman (Box 369)
    - T52.2: Speakers' Bureau (Box 370)
    - T52.16: Speakers - Washington (Box 370)
    - T52.2: Speakers (Box 370)
      Includes Mrs. James K. Blake and Mrs. Charles G. Morris.
      Arranged alphabetically.
    - T52.2.200: Rallies and speakers, Fairfield County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.300: Rallies and speakers, Hartford County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.400: Rallies and speakers, Litchfield County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.500: Rallies and speakers, Middlesex County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.600: Rallies and speakers, New Haven County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.700: Rallies and speakers, New London County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.800: Rallies and speakers, Tolland County (Box 370)
    - T52.2.900: Rallies and speakers, Windham County (Box 370)
    - T52.2 Speakers Bureau Transferred (Box 370)
    - T52.2: Speakers' correspondence (Box 371)
    - T52.2: National Committee Speakers Bureau (Box 371)
    - T52.2.200: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Fairfield County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.300: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Hartford County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.400: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Litchfield County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.500: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Middlesex County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.200: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, New Haven County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.200: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, New London County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.200: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Tolland County (Box 371)
    - T52.2.200: Towns - Rallies - Speakers, Windham County (Box 371)
    - T52.3: Miss Wilkes (Box 372)
    - T52.3: Mrs. Shelby (Box 372)
    - T52.3: Transferred - Information & Research including Mrs. Shelby's letters (Box 372)
    - T52.4: Material for Connecticut Bulletin, news items & releases (Box 372)
    - T52.4: Press releases (Box 372)
    - T52.5: Press releases from Washington (Box 372)
    - T53: Registration (Box 372)
    - T53: Registration of women (Box 372)
    - T53: Transferred - Registration (Box 372)
    - T53.16: Transferred - National Committee registration (Box 372)
    - T54: Transferred - Delivery reductions (Box 373)
    - T54: Commercial economy and reduction of deliveries (Box 373)
    - T54.1: "Victory conferences" - Mrs. Hayward (Box 373)
    - T54.16: National Delivery Committee reductions (Box 373)
    - T55: Liberty Loan (Box 373)
    - T55.1: War savings (Box 373)
    - T55.16: National Committee Liberty Loan (Box 373)
    - T57: Medical service - Dr. Mead (Box 373)
    - T57: Medical service for women, nurses, etc. (Box 373)
    - T57: Transferred September 18, 1918 - Medical service (Box 373)
    - T57.1: Nurses (Box 374)
    - T57.2: Correspondence re nurses and influenza epidemic (Box 374)
    - T57.16: National Committee Medical Service (Box 374)
    - T57.1-16: National Committee Nursing (Box 374)
    - T58: Transferred September 18, 1918 - Food Administration - Food conservation - Miscellaneous (Box 374)
    - T58: Food Conservation and Home Economics - Production (Box 374)
    - T58: Food conservation - Miss Sprague, Mr. Scoville, Miss Birdsey (Box 374)
    - T58.16: National Committee - Food production, Food conservation, Home economics (Box 374)
    - T58: Transferred September 18, 1918 - National Committee Food Production and Home Economics (Box 374)
    - T59: Food production (Box 375)
    - T59.1: Replies from agricultural schools (Box 375)
    - T59.16: National Committee Food Production (Box 375)
    - T59.1: Dorothy Weir (Box 375)
    - T59.1-16: National Committee Women in Agriculture (Box 375)
    - T59.1.22: Reports from states concerning women in agriculture (Box 375)
    - T59.1: Land army (Box 375)
    - T59.2: Land army - Miscellaneous (Box 375)
    - 59.3: Farm Bureau (Box 376)
    - T60: Maintenance of existing social service agencies; Social service work; Day nurseries (Box 376)
    - T60: Elinor Prudden (Box 376)
    - T60: Social service (Box 376)
    - T60: Maintenance of existing social service agencies - material sent by Mrs. Buel on disbanding of committee (Box 376)
    - T60: Maintenance of social security agencies (Box 376)
    - T60.1: Day nurseries - Mrs. Dodge (Box 376)
    - T60.16: National Committee Social Service Maintenance of Existing Social Service Agencies (Box 376)
    - T61: Child welfare (Box 376)
    - T61.1.01: Organization of Committee on Children's Year (Box 376)
    - T61.16: National Committee (Box 376)
    - T61.1: Committee on Child Welfare to inaugurate the Children's Year (Box 376)
    - T61.1: Dr. Walter H. Brown (Box 376)
    - T62: Woman workers (Box 376)
    - T62: Mrs. J. P. Esmonde (Box 377)
    - T62.15: National Committee Woman in Industry (Box 377)
    - T62.2: Responses re employment of women (Box 377)
    - T63: Finance - Treasurer - Mrs. Bumstead (Box 377)
    - T63.1: Receipts (Box 377)
    - T63.2: Acknowledgement of contributions and donations (Box 377)
    - T64: Health and recreation (Box 377)
    - T64: Miss Anna W. Coale, "Organization for girls' work" (Box 377)
    - T65: Red Cross and Allied relief, 2 folders (Box 377)
    - T65.16: National Committee Red Cross (Box 377)
    - T65.22: Red Cross states other than Connecticut (Box 377)
    - T66: National Propaganda (Box 366)
    - T66: Educational Propaganda (Box 377)
    - T66: Educational propaganda - Miss Susan D. Huntington (Box 377)
    - T66.1: Requests from schools in answer to circular letter Feb. 21 leaflet "A French General's Tribute to the First American Dead" (Box 378)
    - T66.16: Weekly Bulletin issued by the War Department - Commission on Training Camp Activities (Box 378)
    - T66.16: National Committee Educational Propaganda (Box 378)
    - T100: Town organization (Box 378)
    - T100: County chairmen (Box 378)
    - T200: Fairfield County (Box 378-379)
      Arranged alphabetically by town.
    - T300: Hartford County (Box 379-380)
    - T400: Litchfield County (Box 380-381)
    - T500: Middlesex County (Box 381)
    - T600: New Haven County (Box 381-382)
    - T700: New London County (Box 382-383)
    - T800: Tolland County (Box 383)
    - T900: Windham County (Box 383)
  - 75. "Pamphlet file", 1917-1919
    - T06: Programs on meetings (Box 384)
    - T16: National Council publications (Box 384)
    - T22: Pamphlets from other states (Box 385-386)
    - T25: Food exhibits (Box 386)
    - T51: Motor messenger service (Box 386)
    - T52: Publicity State Council and Woman's Committee (Box 386)
    - T52.2 Speakers' Bureau and material (Box 386)
    - T54: Delivery & reduction (Box 386)
    - T55: Liberty loan & thrift stamps (Box 386)
    - T56: Courses in instruction (Box 386)
    - T57: Medical services (Box 386)
    - T58: Food conservation (Box 387)
    - T59: Food production & land army (Box 387)
    - T61: Child welfare (Box 387)
    - T62: Women workers (Box 388)
    - T64: Health and recreation (Box 388)
    - T65: Red Cross & Allied relief (Box 388)
    - T66: Educational propaganda (Box 388)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 388)
  - 76. Subject index to classified file, 1917-1919 (Box 424)
    Card index (headed "Filing") to materials in Entry 74 above.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - 77. Card list of towns and localities (Box 424)
    Card list (headed "towns with code numbers") of names of towns and committees, with references and code numbers.
    Arranged alphabetically by place name.
  - 78. List of committee personnel, 1917-1918 (Box 424)
    Card list of names of key committee members, with addresses and file numbers in Item 74 above.
    Arranged by committee.
  - 79. Notes on suggested chairmen, 1917 (Box 424)
    Cards with names of suggested town chairmen for Woman's Committee.
    Arranged by town.
  - 80. Washington circulars and orders, 1917-1919 (Box 389-390)
    Mimeographed circulars, general orders, bulletins, etc., issued by the Council of National Defense, Woman's Committee.
    Arranged chronologically.
  - 81. Connecticut circulars and orders, 1917-1918 (Box 391)
    Directives and circulars issued by the headquarters of the Connecticut Council of Defense Woman's Committee or Woman's Division.
    Arranged, in part, by subject.
  - 82. Service registration forms, 1917
    Questionnaires completed by women volunteering for various kinds of public service work. Administered by the National League for Woman's Service.
    - Forms 1 - 1599 (Abell - Fenn) (Box 392A)
    - Forms 600 - 913 (Filon - Wiley) (Box 392B)
    - Special series, Forms 691 - 771 (Box 392B)
      May be duplicates.
  - 83. Director's office files, 1917-1919 (Box 393)
    Marked "Personal folders", these include correspondence of several high officials of the Woman's Division (Caroline Ruutz-Rees, Mrs. Perrin C. Galpin, Mrs. T. Belknap Beach, Mrs. John W. Alsop, Margaret T. Corwin and others) pertaining to the organization of the Division, its work, the work of the Connecticut Woman Suffrage Association, the recruiting of student nurses, etc.
    Grouped by subject or person.
  - 84. Minutes, 1917-1918; 2 folders (Box 394)
    Minutes of meetings of the Woman's Committee and its Executive Board, with related material.
  - 84a. Minutes of the Middlesex County Woman's Committee, 1917 October - 1918 December; 1 folder (Box 394)
  - 85. Correspondence on "Back to School" drive, 1919; 2 folders (Box 394)
  - 86. Clippings, 1917-1918; 4 folders (Box 394)
    Newspaper clippings pertaining to "war interviews", registration of women, nurses, and other women's interests.
  - 87. Mailing lists, 1917-1919 (Box 395)
    Lists of individuals, officials, and organizations involved in or related to the work of the Woman's Division. Included are two binders of typed lists, a notebook "Register" and card lists of Executive Committee members, office staff, town chairmen and others.
  - 88. Photographs of women leaders, circa 1918 (Box 396)
    Photographs, evidently prepared for publication, of Woman's Division officials and town chairmen.
  - 89. "Collected materials", 1917-1919 (Box 397-398)
    See note for Item 12.
- Series 15. New London County Auxiliary Committee
  - 90. General file, 1917-1918
    Correspondence and memoranda, with related reference material.
    - Aliens (Box 399)
    - Auxiliary Committee (Box 399)
    - Available Autos (Box 399)
    - Badges (Box 399)
    - Binoculars (Box 399)
    - Aliens (Box 399)
    - Bozrah Town Committee (Box 399)
    - Bulletin, County, No. 3; Town Bulletin No. 2 (Box 399)
    - Bulletin boards (Box 399)
    - Bulletin, Town, No. 8 (Box 399)
    - Aliens (Box 399)
    - Bulletins, Summary of County and Town (Box 399)
    - Charitable organzations - Bulletin No. 1 (Box 399)
    - Charitable and patriotic work - Town bulletin No. 6 (Box 399)
    - Coal deliveries - T. W. Russell - Fuel Administrator (Box 399)
    - Colchester Town Committee (Box 399)
    - Connecticut State Council of Defense - Hartford, 4 folders (Box 400)
    - Disloyalty - County Bulletin No. 12 - Town Bulletin No. 11 (Box 400)
    - Drafted men, Send off of (Box 400)
    - East Lyme Town Committee (Box 400)
    - Economy through deliveries (Box 400)
    - Expenses, Town - County Reports - Budget - County Bulletin No. 6 (Box 400)
    - Fairs, 1917 (Box 400)
    - Farm Bureau work (Box 400)
    - Fire prevention (Box 400)
    - Foods - Hoover - Scoville (Box 400)
    - Food Administration Bulletins (Box 400)
    - Forms (Box 401)
    - Four Minute Men (Box 401)
    - Franklin Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Griswold Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Groton Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Joint meeting - County Bulletin No. 4 (Box 401)
    - Lebanon Town Committee, 2 folders (Box 401)
    - Ledyard Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Liberty Chorus - County Bulletin No. 15 - Town Bulletin No. 14 (Box 401)
    - Lisbon Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Lists of drafter men - County Bulletin No. 7 - Town Bulletin No. 7 (Box 401)
    - Lyme Town Committee (Box 401)
    - Mercer, F. W. - Treasurer (Box 401)
    - Montville Town Committee (Box 402)
    - National Bulletin No. 79 (Box 402)
    - National League Woman's Service (Box 402)
    - Naturalized citizens - Foreign born population - County Bulletin No. 10 - Town Bulletin No. 10 (Box 402)
    - New London Town Committee (Box 402)
    - North Stonington Town Committee (Box 402)
    - Norwich Town Committee (Box 402)
    - Old Lyme Town Committee (Box 402)
    - Preston Town Committee (Box 402)
    - Playground and Recreation Association (Box 402)
    - Posting agents for bulletins - County Bulletin No. 9 - Town Bulletin No. 9 (Box 402)
    - Pupil nurses (Box 402)
    - Rallies (Box 402)
    - Recruiting (Box 402)
    - Regular Army Recruiters Week, 1917 June 24-30 (Box 402)
    - Salem Town Committee (Box 402)
    - Service Flags (Box 402)
    - Soldiers and Sailors Business Committee - Town Bulletin No. 4 (Box 402)
    - Speakers (Box 402)
    - Sprague Town Committee, 2 folders (Box 402)
    - Stationery (Box 403)
    - Stonington Town Committee, 2 folders (Box 403)
    - Town Committees, Changes in - County Bulletin No. 11 and No. 5 (Box 403)
    - Voluntown Town Committee (Box 403)
    - War Bureau (Box 403)
    - War Convention (Box 403)
    - War Library - County Bulletin No. 13 - Town Bulletin No. 12 (Box 403)
    - War risk insurance (Box 403)
    - War savings stamps (Box 403)
    - War savings thrift plan (Box 403)
    - Waterford Town Committee, 2 folders (Box 403)
    - YMCA campaign (Box 403)
- Series 16. Exhibit Material
  - 91. Exhibit and demonstration material
    See Related Material section for items transferred to the Museum of Connecticut History.
    - Photographs (Box 404)
      Exhibits at Exhibition Hall, Charter Oak Park, Harford, September 2-6, 1918.
      Removed from photo album.
    - Photostats of exhibits and posters (Box 405)
      Posters are in oversize.
- Series 17. Miscellaneous
  - 92. Unfiled and unidentified material
    These are "left over" items which have not been identified with any of the series or groups listed above but which were found with the Council of Defense records.
    - Blank certificates for service in Four Minute Men, Boys' Working Reserve, and Public Service Reserve (Box 406)
    - Photograph of major Howard A. Giddings (Box 406)
    - Photostats of organization charts of Council of Defense, Bridgeport Disaster Relief Plan, New Haven War Bureau (Box 406)
    - Photostats of plans of "Economical hot air furnaces" (Box 406)
    - Unfiled papers (Box 407)
      Papers dealing with Council of National defense policies, translations from German-language newspapers, New East, reconstruction, etc.
    - Documents (Box 408)
      Published by various official and unofficial agencies pertaining to war and post-war programs. (Included are the first and second annual reports of the Council of National defense.)